[
  {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "The three important goals of data communications are correct delivery, accurate delivery and______________",
      "answers": [
          "late delivery",
          "on the spot delivery",
          "timely delivery",
          "delivery on the next day"
      ],
      "Correct_answer": "timely delivery"
  },
  {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "______________ standards are highly desirable because anyone can use them.",
      "answers": [
          "rule",
          "protocol",
          "law",
          "option"
      ],
      "Correct_answer": "law"
  },
  {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "The fundamental basis of data communications is _______.",
      "answers": [
          "Free",
          "Open",
          "Closed",
          "Ready"
      ],
      "Correct_answer": "Open"
  },
  {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "The time required for passing energy from one point to another is called ______________.",
      "answers": [
          "light",
          "electricity",
          "voltage",
          "signal propagation"
      ],
      "Correct_answer": "signal propagation"
  },
  {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "______________ signals are continuous in nature.",
      "answers": [
          "propagation delay",
          "movement delay",
          "change delay",
          "passing delay"
      ],
      "Correct_answer": "propagation delay"
  },
  {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "______________ signals are on-off in nature.",
      "answers": [
          "Analog",
          "Digital",
          "Mixed",
          "None of the above"
      ],
      "Correct_answer": "Analog"
  },
  {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "The concept of ______________ can be understood with the help of the example of a waterpipe.",
      "answers": [
          "Analog",
          "Digital",
          "Mixed",
          "None of the above"
      ],
      "Correct_answer": "Digital"
  },
  {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "______________ showed that any waveform can be shown as made-up of a number of smaller",
      "answers": [
          "analog signals",
          "digital signals",
          "amplitude",
          "bandwidth"
      ],
      "Correct_answer": "digital signals"
  },
  {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "The strength of a signal at any point of time is called as its ______________.",
      "answers": [
          "Fourier",
          "Newton",
          "Einstein",
          "Hartley"
      ],
      "Correct_answer": "Hartley"
  },
  {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "The time required for the completion of one signal cycle is its ______________",
      "answers": [
          "amplitude",
          "frequency",
          "period",
          "phase"
      ],
      "Correct_answer": "amplitude"
  },
  {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "The number of cycles completed by a signal in one second is its ______________",
      "answers": [
          "amplitude",
          "frequency",
          "period",
          "phase"
      ],
      "Correct_answer": "amplitude"
  },
  {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "The unit used to measure frequency is ______________.",
      "answers": [
          "hertz",
          "volts",
          "ampere",
          "seconds"
      ],
      "Correct_answer": "ampere"
  },
  {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "The de jure standards apply because of ______________.",
      "answers": [
          "conventions",
          "agreement",
          "regulation",
          "choice"
      ],
      "Correct_answer": "agreement"
  }
]